FABIO A. NAVARRETE HIGUERA E-mail: fabioanh@gmail.com

Tel: +32 493169603

Location: Berlin, Germany

General Information:



Software engineer born 1988 in Colombia. I enjoy solving scientific and technical problems and I'm eager always learn new things. Creativity is one of my main drivers, because of this I using the different skills possess. I like to keep my interests I diversified and thrive developing I've software. been working professionally for around 9 years, mostly with Java. I've been part of different software teams in 5 different countries using a wide range of technologies. I've been also using Python and Kotlin in academic and personal projects. strongest skills are related to design and development of RESTful APIs. join eager to а challenging environment where I can learn new tools and share my knowledge. At the moment I to contribute would like environmental cause.

Academic Background:



Systems Engineer (Bachelor of Science) -Universidad Nacional de Colombia - 2010

Information Technology Tools:



Java 👙	Python 🦺	Linux
Spring 🕏	Postgres 📭	Flutter
Hibernate 🗣	Oracle	TensorFlow
RESTful {}	Jira💠	JUnit
Git 🚸	JMeter /jMeter	Mockito
AWS aws	Jenkins 🧌	Kotlin
Solr 🧶	Google Cloud	2
MongoDB 🌗	Kubernetes 🚳	
Spring Boot		

Miscellaneous:

Interested in the study of and Artificial systems Intelligence. about social simulations anthropology. Amateur drums player. like to learn, teach, and improve my languages knowledge. Finally, I also like hiking and contemplation of nature.

Job History:



ubitricity(Jun 2021 - Present) Development of platform charging point provider. Rest API spring-boot microservices on Google Cloud. Scrum team.



IPlytics(Sept 2020 - May 2021) Intelectual property platform development. Web App using Boot. Cloud migration, Azure



Kubernetes.

Proximus (Feb 2018 - Jun 2019 Belgium) Web-shop development mostly involved with the Rest API. Scrum teams, project with around 30 people total.



Adneom (Jun 2016 - Dec 2017 Belgium) Consultancy work for ENGIE: support during migration of web application backend from Java to Python. BPost: JEE app.



Advaita (Nov 2013 - Sep 2015 USA) Development of a RESTful API using Spring, in order to commercialise a stalled product for a bioinformatics startup.



Globant (Jun 2012 - Oct 2013 Colombia) JEE development. Worked on several applications for external clients. Additional tests automation tasks.



Spoken Languages:

English - C1 level French - B2 level German - A2 level Italian - A2 evel Spanish - Mother tongue